I created Paperclip to enable people to
run a zero human business. Andrew, look
at this. We've one shop an entire
company. We just released companies.sh,
which is like the app store for aentic
companies. I don't want to oversell it.
I just want to show what's possible
today. Okay. Let's do a screen share.
I'll show you how to use paperclipip.
>> Presented by Zapier, the AI automation
company.
>> You want to show me your company first?
>> Sure. This would be the company that I
use for running Paperclip itself. It's
actually pretty small right now. We've
got the CEO, we've got the CTO, which
has a lot of the uh like coders under
it. So for example,
>> and all of these are agents. The CTO is
an agent, the coder is an agent, etc.
>> Yeah, that's right. And my my main coder
that I use would be either um Claude or
Codeex. You know, I think if you ask any
person that uses AI agents daytoday,
they can tell you that they all have
really different personalities and
different strengths and weaknesses.
Okay. But before we before we continue,
because you're going to go deeper and
show me how this works, I got to ask
you, why am I looking at a cartoon and
not a human being?
>> Yeah. Yes. So, um I come from the crypto
world and like I don't mind having uh my
anonymity and that's just something I
like to carry through.
>> All right. I'm the opposite. I want as
much attention as possible, but let's
continue.
>> So, I see this you were saying about all
these different developers. This I so
far all I'm looking at is an org chart.
This is not the special part. Show me
the special part of paperclipip. One of
the reasons that I created paperclipip
was because I was um trying to build
companies in the terminal using claude
code and cursor and I had way way too
many things going on and I would come
back and I wasn't able to remember what
anybody was doing or what anyone was
working on. So, with Paperclip, what
you're actually able to do is um keep
everything managed like you would with a
task manager and all the conversations
are tracked, all of the costs are
tracked, and everything that your agents
do, you can uh go back and see how they
did it, if they did a good job, if
something went wrong, how to fix it.
Something else that you can do with
Paperclip is it helps you manage your
agents instructions. If you're working
with AI agents, that's one of the main
things that you need to know is that
your agents wake up every time you hit
them. They wake up and they're insanely
capable, but they have no idea who they
are or what they're supposed to be
working on or what they worked on
yesterday. Paperclip makes that easy
because, you know, I can have my UX
designer have a certain sort of
instructions on how it's supposed to
work. I can have my video writer uh have
work. And then you can also configure
skills. So, I don't know if you've seen
um skills.sh, which is a uh a website
that a lot of people use for managing
their agent skills. Have you used this?
>> No, I haven't.
>> Yeah. So, this is from the guys at
Verscell, and it's basically a way that
you can teach your agents different
types of abilities. So, for example, um
web design best practices, how to make
videos with Remotion, how to generate AI
images. So um this is a really powerful
way that if you're using claude code or
codeex um or any kind of coding agent to
do your to run your business, you really
want to look at different skills that
other people have created because it
gives your agent superpowers. So for
example,
this morning um we released a um a new
website companies.sh which gives you one
command installs of entire companies and
we'll talk about this. Mhm.
>> Um, but one of the things that I needed
was I actually needed a video for it.
And so I asked my AI agent to create a
video. I asked my CEO. I said, "Hey, um,
I created a new issue. I said, um, can
you hire a video writer and, uh, give
him the remotion skill?" So, this was
something that I did earlier this
morning and the agent was hired. And I
can look here and I can see yeah write
the script for a 60-cond video about the
companies.sh launch. So I asked it to
write a plan and it wrote this plan
which is um here's what the audience
will take away the messaging hierarchy
shot by shot of what the video should
be. Um and then it used this remotion
skill which I downloaded from here to
actually create the video for me. What
it was able to do was it was able to
take um the the brand guide that I had
already set up for Paperclip as well as
a few of the basic ideas that I had for
how we were going to pitch this
company's video. Instead of launching
this tweet with just text, I actually
had this interactive animated video for
the launch.
>> But now at what point did you give it
the skill?
>> When I hired the agent, I simply told
the CEO to give him that skill.
>> Oh, I see. So, you got the skill and
then you sent it over. You sent the link
over to the skill and you said, "Hey,
CEO, create somebody who's going to make
a video for me. Use the skill." Boom.
That's it.
>> Exactly. That's all you have to do. So,
you could come here and say, um, you
know, let's say I want someone who can
make Excel spreadsheets, for example. I
could copy this in here and I could go
to my CEO and say uh we need a like data
analyst who has uh data skills for
Excel. Um and I would assign this to our
CEO and we'll say uh give him this
skill. So we'll let that run in the
background. Maybe we can come back to it
a bit later.
>> And then Okay. And that's how you end up
having another agent who comes in with
skills. And what are we looking at here?
These are all the skills.
>> Yeah. So these would be the skills that
you have built into your organization.
So um we have a uh humanizer skill which
is used for helping your AI write a
little bit better. We also have a a
memory skill here which is um the TGOF's
parah method of memory. Um this skill is
actually from Nat Eli who I know that
you've uh spoken with before and this
gives your agents uh memory over a long
period of time. So,
>> and these skills right here are skills
that are universal to everyone who's
working or every agent that's working
for me.
>> Um, so you can choose because one of the
downsides of models of today is that if
you load too many skills in, they start
to lose track and your performance
degrades. You really only want to enable
the skills for the agents that are
actually going to use them. All right,
I'm I'm getting this project management
built for agents with skills and memory
features that agents are going to need.
Let's take a look at what you created
and what you launched, which is now
basically an app store where instead of
adding apps to my life, I'm now adding
companies and these are the different
types of companies that I can have. Walk
me through what what's in here so far.
And obviously we're recording this on
launch day, so there's not that much.
Um, one of the things that I have
noticed, and I'm sure you guys have too,
is that there are so many new um, links
or repos shared every day on different
ways that you can u make your agents
better. So, for example, a really
popular popular one is this one GStack
by Gary Tan of Y Combinator where he
provides a set of skills. He's the
president CEO of Y Combinator. He has
skills in here that um let you have a uh
office hours like your NYC and they're
quizzing you for um like if you need
help or if you're trying to build your
business, they have how to do planning,
how to plan engineering, design
consultations, all these things, right?
So
>> essentially he's taken all the different
things that they bring to Y Combinator
founders who are part of the accelerator
and he's turned them into skills here
that you can invoke if you're in claude
code. I've used them. It's actually
helpful. All right. And what you did was
you say, "Well, if he's got all of
these, he's essentially creating a
company where agents can take on these
different roles. I'm now going to make
it into a one-click, oneshot company
creation based on his model."
>> That's exactly right. So, when you
install um GStack into your paperclipip
instance, you will get um the agents
with all of their skills installed. So
now you can start to use GStack um from
paperclip with in a way that's very very
easy.
>> So he recommends for example having uh a
QA engineer look at the work that you've
that was created and so you've added
that role right there.
>> That's right. And one of the things that
I am finding is that um there are a lot
of patterns when using agents that are
not really clear. But in reality, a lot
of the best companies have um relatively
sophisticated patterns of agents
checking each other's work, agents
giving work back to one another. But
there really is been no place where you
can actually share those patterns with
other people. And so that's what we've
tried to build here. Um even though
you'll notice this isn't a paperclipip
uh domain. So the reason is is because
this is a standard that we hope for
other companies to use um to make
sharable companies.
>> Okay.
>> And the idea is as people learn these
patterns that make their agents more
effective, we'll all be sharing them
with each other and um all benefit as as
a result.
>> Okay. Can I see one of these companies
working and then we'll launch one right
now together?
>> Yeah, absolutely. So um here for example
would be um the Don Cheetos game studio
which is quite large and um so you can
see here they've got creative directors,
narrative directors, art directors and
let's see here. So um
>> this is an active paperclip experience
right here, right?
>> Um yes. So, I would say this that like
one of the things paperclipip is three
weeks old today and I would say that one
of the things that we're still working
on is making sure that um paperclip
keeps your agents working when you want
them to work. Uh there's a feature we're
working on that's not out yet called
maximizer mode and it will ensure that
your agents never stop working. So um
here what we've done here is we we
created a first game where we said you
know we're making a bullet hell game in
uh this game engine called GDO. Um we
can come here and we could you know we
could basically ask the CEO like um
follow up on all the work and like keep
people moving. [laughter] You probably
shouldn't have to do this but uh
>> okay
>> you know
yeah there we go. So starting with um
this issue
um what the CEO will essentially be able
to do is come through here and make sure
that these things have actually
succeeded. Right. So we've got a project
set up in GDAU a folder structure for
players, enemies, weapons, things like
that.
>> Okay.
>> Um we could also come over to the Gstack
if you wanted to.
>> So this is a company you created using
Gary Tan's Gstack. This is this is what
you showed me the template of. And maybe
we can create this together now. Sure.
Yeah, absolutely. Yeah.
>> By the way, one big question that came
up when I showed how Katherine had set
this up is do you have to use Claude's
models for this?
>> You actually do not have to use Claude's
models for this. You need
>> Wait, just describe what you just did
right here. You just you're doing what
here?
>> Oh, yes. Okay. So, I have switched to um
a terminal.
>> Yep. Of course.
>> Terminal app on my Mac.
And if you want to install paperclipip
itself uh for the first time, you can
call uh paperclipip AI onboarding. So
npx paperclipip AI onboard and that will
walk you through the onboarding.
>> And I need to do this before I install
one of the companies, one of the
companies.
>> You don't have to actually uh the good
news is is that it will actually um
install Paperclip for you. So all we
need to do here is we can go to the
website and copy the command. Uh did
that off screen. We'll paste it in. npx
npx is is a tool that most Macs have
installed.
>> Um, companies.sh add uh paperclipip AI
companies gstack. And this will run for
a minute.
>> And it'll say what service do you want
to import your company to? And there we
go. We'll get that imported into it.
Gives us a bit of a listing here of
saying all right, how many agents are
you going to get? How many skills are
you going to get? And just confirm that
we want to import it. All right. So we
can switch back over to this new
company. Um something else with the
models is there's a tool called open
code that uses um this website open
router and they have a um a leaderboard
of models that people use there. Um and
some of these model this is a place
where this is a place where a AI model
companies test out their new models
before they release them to the public.
So sometimes Grock will have their model
here under an anonymous name. Um and and
they often have free models. So for
example, here you can see there's step
3.5 flash free. There were a couple
other models last week that were very
very high quality. So you can actually
send your agents um here and get
essentially free inference.
>> All right. What about uh the web
experience? Can I actually access the
project management experience somewhere
else?
>> Yes. So um we will be creating a
paperclipip cloud hosted version but for
now what you can do is there is a tool
that a lot of people use called tail
scale and uh tail scale has a free plan.
It's actually very very handy because
you are able to connect your phone to
your computer through the internet. So,
what I do is I run paperclipip on my
laptop and then I run tail scale on my
laptop and my phone and so when I'm at u
you know when I'm out and about the the
paperclip has a mobile version and it
works quite well. I use it all the time.
>> Okay, let's stick with what you were
doing before which was now you are
installing Gary Tan's uh company. Is it
is it set up? It is.
>> This is what we just created. That was
fast.
>> What we It's amazing. So, you know, do
we have a business idea that we want to
ask Gary Tan his advice on? So, like
>> use office hours and ask um advice for
our new business idea, which is
>> um here's here's a new business idea.
Install Paperclip uh for people. I've
been noticing that OpenClaw has got this
b this uh economy of people who are
installing OpenClaw for first timers.
I think with all of these technologies
there's there people who are watching it
who don't want to do it themselves who
want some customization.
Let's see what what happens when we do
this.
Now the thing that when I've used this
skill in the past the thing that I like
about it is how fast I go back and forth
with uh with opus to ask questions and
answer its questions and so on. here by
creating a ticket. Aren't I just slowing
it down?
>> I would say that um if you simply wanted
to kind of chat with uh the office hours
skill and you wanted the fastest
response time, you can still use cloud
for that um directly. But if you find
that you are trying to manage 50
different things with your agents and
you can't remember what every tab is
doing and you don't know what they're
doing, then that's where Paperclip
really shines for you.
>> Um, so we'll we'll wait for this to go.
Maybe we can look back over here and see
ah yes, so we did hire this data analyst
agent from earlier. We can approve it
from the CEO. We can see here that our
uh data analyst is now part of our team.
So he's got the XLS uh X skill where he
could work with Google Sheets and make
data for us.
>> Okay. All right. And coming back to this
company that we just created. Um
essentially now I can just keep giving
it tasks and understand that the
different agents will work with each
other based on uh the GStack
methodology.
>> That's right. Um, so while we're waiting
for uh the office hours to come back and
give us some advice, um, one of the
things that we could do is we could hop
back over to um, paper and I could show
you routines. So routines is where you
have work that needs to happen on a
recurring basis. So for example, I use
my Twitter bookmarks all the time to
store ideas for things that I think will
make Paperclip better. Um, so for
example, I wrote this routine that says,
"Hey, I want you to pull my bookmarks
and write up strategy for paperclip. I
have a strategic ops guide." And I say,
you know, this is my plan book like sync
the bookmarks and here are the
guidelines for how I expect you to like
make this plan. Then what I'm able to do
is um every morning I come in here and I
can see that uh here's my bookmark
strategy report. and say, "Okay, there's
um this tweet that you bookmarked around
Enthropic had a tweet for a new
heartbeat pattern. You should look into
that." Or here's a way to track um it's
called telemetry, which is like the way
to like track what agents are working or
what's not. Um and so on. And so what
actually happens is when I show up every
morning, my agents have actually started
to do some leg work from things that I
was thinking about yesterday. So, I can
actually come in here and say, "Hey, why
don't you work out like building that as
a feature?" And I'm able to sort of like
have my agents work for me while I'm
asleep.
>> Ah, yeah.
>> So, all right, office hours
complete. Oh, okay. So, here we go.
Here's our office hours for this new
business idea. Install a paperclipip for
people. Forcing questions, demand
reality. Who's paying for this today? Is
there demand for installation or is it
just a friction? What happens without
you? And so on, right? Like we can walk
through this and kind of Yeah, here's
the hard truth. Services don't scale. So
yeah, there we go. These are some first
recommendations from Gary about our
paperclipip install business.
>> Essentially, he's saying this is not a
good business idea.
>> Yeah. Yeah. [laughter]
He's here to find out now.
>> Fair. Yeah, fair enough. Okay, I'm
getting this. The vision that you have
for this now is that as new
methodologies for running a company come
up online, people will have a place
where they can share them and others
will have a place where they could go
and install this whole business.
Oneclick install and the whole company
will start to run and paperclipip will
be what's keeping them all organized.
>> That's exactly it.
>> After you've created a company that you
think is good, that you think other
people would want to use, um, you know,
this is the company that I use for
Paperclip itself. You can come here and
click export company and it will export
the company in the format that uh that
you can use to now share. Let's see if I
can make this window a bit bigger. There
we go.
>> So it creates a company export for you
with a read me and diagram all these
things and you can now submit that to
your on GitHub or submit it to us and uh
it's all packaged up nicely. Why didn't
you make it into a marketplace where I
can sell these company structures?
>> That's a great idea. I think we're going
to we'll probably make a, you know, claw
hub. Nate Elias already has a claw mart
uh where you can buy and sell individual
agents. Maybe we create something, you
know, like clip mart or something that
that that that where you can use it or,
you know, maybe we team up with him. I
don't know. I'd have to ask him.
>> I love where you're going with this. All
the agents in one. Easy to install, easy
to get started. In many ways, I find
that this is much easier than using
using OpenClaw and then creating sub
aents there and managing them and so on.
It's just allin-one right here. And of
course, for anyone who's using OpenClaw,
they can bring their OpenClaw into
paperclip. All right.
>> Yep. Absolutely. And I love OpenClaw.
It's a great piece of software, but I
created paperclip because my OpenClaw
just sort of started to fall apart and I
couldn't understand what it was doing or
what it was remembering or forgetting.
And so, yeah, Paperclip is designed to
be more human friendly. All of us start
off by creating some kind of project
management. Now it's all here.